<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Copeka&#39;s Menu - Espresso - Chia - Food -  Bakery - Beer, Wine &amp; Cocktails on Copeka Coffee</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Copeka&#39;s Menu - Espresso - Chia - Food -  Bakery - Beer, Wine &amp; Cocktails on Copeka Coffee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu</title>
      <link>/menus/menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 06:28:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/menus/menu/</guid>
      <description>fresh pastries made daily $(various prices) ask your barista about today&amp;rsquo;s selection (mostly :v:) (:gf: options)
house made granola with local honey $$ milk — 5.25 $$ yogurt — 6.5 $$ hello — 2.3 $$ yogurt and fresh seasonal fruit — 8.5 $$ milk and yogurt options are :d: or :v:
aardvark toasts all of our toasts are served on our house made aardvark bread, a seedy rustic loaf of legend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>song and dance show</title>
      <link>/events/2018/song-and-dance-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 16:25:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2018/song-and-dance-show/</guid>
      <description>the chickens were happy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copeka&#39;s Menu - Espresso - Chia - Food -  Bakery - Beer, Wine &amp; Cocktails</title>
      <link>/events/foodmenus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/foodmenus/</guid>
      <description> Drinks Americano Au Lait Breve Cappuccino Chai Cold Brew Cortado Cuban Drip Espresso Golden Latte Hot Chocolate LaCroix Latte Mocha Pour Over Shakerato Steamer Tea Vanilla Latte
Cocktails, Beer &amp;amp; Wine Boozerato Cocktail Chai Toddy Cocktail
Food Aardvark Toast Burrito Basic Burrito Kicked Fritatta Soup/Chili Soup/Chili
#Bakery
Daily Copeka Cookies Cinnamon Roll Baked Oatmeal Scones Charley’s Cookies Unicon Horns Granola
Regular Paleo Pop Tarts
Alcohol </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copeka&#39;s Menu - Espresso - Chia - Food -  Bakery - Beer, Wine &amp; Cocktails</title>
      <link>/menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/menu/</guid>
      <description>::: column two commaList
Drinks  Americano Au Lait Breve Cappuccino Chai Cold Brew Cortado Cuban Drip Espresso Golden Latte Hot Chocolate LaCroix Latte Mocha Pour Over Shakerato Steamer Tea Vanilla Latte  Cocktails, Beer &amp;amp; Wine  Boozerato Cocktail Chai Toddy Cocktail   :::  ::: column two commaList
Food  Aardvark Toast Burrito Basic Burrito Kicked Fritatta Soup/Chili Soup/Chili  Bakery Items  Copeka Cookies Cinnamon Roll Baked Oatmeal Scones Charley’s Cookies Unicon Horns Granola  Irregular Offerings  Paleo Pop Tarts  :::</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location &amp; Hours</title>
      <link>/location-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/location-hours/</guid>
      <description>Copeka Coffee Open Daily: 6:30am - 8pm
Open Late: For Events
Closed: Thanksgiving &amp;amp; Christmas Day
1012 N. 5th St
Grand Junction, CO 81501
970.628.0878
Copeka Big Cheese Truck Open Monday - Friday: 10:30am - 2pm Other Hours for Events
Located next to Copeka Coffee along 5th Street</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday, March 23, 2018</title>
      <link>/events/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/23/</guid>
      <description>To-Do
Follow up on floor plan migration with Cece and Larrry. See Larry&amp;rsquo;s emails create migration list of forms and content from SharePoint Test Staff Absence Report with other Managers and Wendy Tech Mart tests SQL Javascript  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday, March 23, 2018</title>
      <link>/projects/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/23/</guid>
      <description>To-Do
Follow up on floor plan migration with Cece and Larrry. See Larry&amp;rsquo;s emails create migration list of forms and content from SharePoint Test Staff Absence Report with other Managers and Wendy Tech Mart tests SQL Javascript  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, March 22, 2018</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/03/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/03/22/</guid>
      <description>Evaluate webform options Layout is the big issue with web form editoring software. I have already evaluated Google Forms and Web Presence. Today I evaluated a long list of
Web Presence Calendar iCal subscriptions. Checked into the issue of why the Staff intranet is not allowing iCal subscriptions
 Rob Snodgrass+−
Hello, how may I help?10:53 AM
A couple of weeks ago, I chatted about iCal feeds on appearing on the calendars of our Staff website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday, March 21, 2018</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/03/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/03/21/</guid>
      <description> Worked with Toby on SSIS Finished Work on Tech Mark migration tests </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday, March 19, 2018</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/03/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/03/19/</guid>
      <description> T-SQL Fundamentals  Read Chapter 5 &amp;ldquo;Table Expressions&amp;rdquo; and worked through first 4 questions  Reviewed content on SharePoint  Created migration notes document  TechMart  started to create Computer order form on Google Forms  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, March 15, 2018</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/03/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/03/15/</guid>
      <description>Web Presence webcast Notes  Messenger App - collects current parent contact info new calendar coming 301 redirects  maintian old links works in WP with moved content automatically can be used for clean short links  custom apps  includes calendars &amp;amp; news for specific school great control of what is in news feeds more and more statistics  stats for channel subscriptions   Safe Arrival  parents can report in advance communcations through the app  Communicate module  quicktip safety related anonymous reporting tool free   Followed up with Mary and BJ about which parts of Web Presence and Communicate we use and how it interfaces with Synergy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday, March 14, 2018</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/03/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/03/14/</guid>
      <description>Staff meeting Review Google Drive transition with Larry, Jenann
Review Tech Mart Options Larry and I looked at the options for the Tech Mart ordering system using either Web Presence or Google Forms:
Web Presence While Presence has a web based GUI to build web forms, it is rather difficult to use for anything beyond very simple forms. It is possible to build very complex
Google Easy to create forms, with minimal workflow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday, March 13, 2018</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/03/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/03/13/</guid>
      <description>Migrated Share Point Files to Google Migrated the following folders from Share Point to the Google Team Drive:
 Technology Operations Support Processes Operating Stats  This should complete the file move. We still need to disable/restrict/delete the file access on Sharepoint.
Created How-To Section for Tech Staff on Web Presence. https://staff.d51schools.org/my_teams/tech_team/how-to/
Screen cast for Incident Management I created a short screencast to show how to create Incident Management Alerts on Web Presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Block Formats</title>
      <link>/about/formatsnew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/formatsnew/</guid>
      <description>Layout &amp;amp; typography ::: margin left
 book  :::
Grand Junction – Text set in all caps gets converted to small-caps by default. This means that acronyms like BBC don’t stand out relative to the rest of the text. Acronyms even $ x^2 $ work with $ x f(x) = 2x^2 + 2/3 $ accents like ÀÊØ. A possessive acronym like CNN&amp;rsquo;s opinion works as well. What about the FCC!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menus</title>
      <link>/about/menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/menu/</guid>
      <description>fresh pastries made daily $(various prices) ask your barista for today&amp;rsquo;s selection (mostly :v:) (:gf: options)
house made granola with local honey $$ milk — 5.25 $$ yogurt — 6.5 $$ hello — 2.3 $$ yogurt and fresh seasonal fruit — 8.5 $$ milk and yogurt options are :d: or :v:
aardvark toasts all of our toasts are served on our house made aardvark bread, a seedy rustic loaf of legend.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>