<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Copeka Coffee</title>
    <link>/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Copeka Coffee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 06:20:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>abc</title>
      <link>/events/abc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 06:20:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/abc/</guid>
      <description>He is the author of “The Art of Computer Programming,” a continuing four-volume opus that is his life’s work. The first volume debuted in 1968, and the collected volumes (sold as a boxed set for about $250) were included by American Scientist in 2013 on its list of books that shaped the last century of science — alongside a special edition of “The Autobiography of Charles Darwin,_”_ Tom Wolfe’s “The Right Stuff,” Rachel Carson’s “Silent Spring” and monographs by Albert Einstein, John von Neumann and Richard Feynman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>song and dance show</title>
      <link>/events/2018/song-and-dance-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 16:25:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2018/song-and-dance-show/</guid>
      <description>the chickens were happy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copeka&#39;s Menu - Espresso - Chia - Food -  Bakery - Beer, Wine &amp; Cocktails</title>
      <link>/events/foodmenus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/foodmenus/</guid>
      <description> Drinks Americano Au Lait Breve Cappuccino Chai Cold Brew Cortado Cuban Drip Espresso Golden Latte Hot Chocolate LaCroix Latte Mocha Pour Over Shakerato Steamer Tea Vanilla Latte
Cocktails, Beer &amp;amp; Wine Boozerato Cocktail Chai Toddy Cocktail
Food Aardvark Toast Burrito Basic Burrito Kicked Fritatta Soup/Chili Soup/Chili
#Bakery
Daily Copeka Cookies Cinnamon Roll Baked Oatmeal Scones Charley’s Cookies Unicon Horns Granola
Regular Paleo Pop Tarts
Alcohol </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday, March 23, 2018</title>
      <link>/events/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/23/</guid>
      <description>To-Do
Follow up on floor plan migration with Cece and Larrry. See Larry&amp;rsquo;s emails create migration list of forms and content from SharePoint Test Staff Absence Report with other Managers and Wendy Tech Mart tests SQL Javascript  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>